Here you need power -gathering efforts
-—-—-
The microplast area is very wide so we have identified
The areas where we see this we need to prioritize the efforts in order to this way
When we make power collections together we can take big steps
In knowledge acquisition
Instead of it happening
Slightly
A little onto the pö that makes it difficult to
Simply collect knowledge
-—-—-
Knowledge ..., a better foundation
For us that we can use when deciding on different instruments and measures
And we know that there has been a lot of research in this area in recent times
But just because it is a fairly new research area so it is
Still quite large knowledge gaps
As we are tamped with so when we are going to make our decisions
-—-—-
If I
Works with plastic
But perhaps not just directly related to research
What do I have to pick up in this research agenda
Yes but we have worked a lot on mapping different sources we had two different government assignments where we have
Looked at that.
What we have seen is that it is very difficult to put an exact figure on how much is spread
But the biggest sources
It is littering, road and tire wear
Synthetic textile fibers and artificial green and also to some extent pellets.
And different intentionally
added microplastics in products.
What do we know
What happens later
These
It is at least 150 million tonnes and that it
Increases by every year and plastic use has increased enormously
So it is being built up
In the seas and the breakdown of plastic occurs very slowly
So even if we stop the supply of microplastics today or within a few years, the formation of microplastic articles will
continue for a long time as there is already so much plastic outside
In our waters
And we have a problem too in that we ...
It is very difficult to clean away microplastics
Once it is in the environment
So we know that after all